Marion Nestle Papers, 1970-2017 MSS.159
Fales Library and Special Collections
Marion Nestle Papers
1970-2017
1980-2013
Fales Library and Special Collections
Nestle, Marion
MSS.159
69.5 Linear Feet in 115 boxes
3 websites in 3 archived websites.
Marion Nestle is a nutritionist, consumer activist, and academic who is one of the pioneers of the food movement. Nestle is Paulette Goddard Professor in the Department of Nutrition, Food Studies, and Public Health at New York University, which she chaired from 1988-2003. Her research examines scientific and socioeconomic influences on food choice, obesity, and food safety, emphasizing the role of food marketing. She is the author of eight books, including Food Politics: How the Food Industry Influences Nutrition and Health; What to Eat; and, with Dr. Malden Nesheim, Why Calories Count: From Science to Politics.
Separated Materials
The Marion Nestle Papers collection was processed even as Nestle continued to donate her vast book collection to the Fales Library. For the most part, Nestle's book library has been catalogued separately from the personal papers. Books that remain in the collection are either annotated or appeared to be directly relevant to the surrounding printed material. A related name search in Bobcat under "Cecily Brownstone" will retrieve records for the entire library.
Arrangement
The Marion Nestle Papers are organized into 17 series. Within these series, files are arranged both alphabetically by subject/author heading and chronologically depending on the nature of the series. Series XV, XVI, and XVII have not be arranged by an archivist; in these series the materials remain in the order in which they were received. Descriptions are at the folder level. The Series are as follows:
Series I: Food Politics
Series II: Safe Food
Series III: What to Eat
Series IV: Pet Food Politics
Series V: Feed Your Pet Right
Series VI: Why Calories Count
Series VII: Professional Activities
Series VIII: Press
Series IX: Photographs
Series X: Printed Material
Series XI: Media
Series XII: Data Storage
Series XIII: Objects
Series XIV: Oversize
Series XV: 2016 Accretion
Series XVI: 2017 Accretion
Series XVII: 2018 Accretion
Series XVIII: Archived Websites
Biographical Note
Marion Nestle is a nutritionist, consumer advocate, and academic whose research examines scientific and socioeconomic influences on food choice, obesity, and food safety, emphasizing the role of food marketing. She is the author of eight books, including Food Politics: How the Food Industry Influences Nutrition and Health; What to Eat; Soda Politics: Taking on Big Soda; and, with Dr. Malden Nesheim, Feed Your Pet Right and Why Calories Count: From Science to Politics.
After completing a Bachelor's Degree in Bacteriology at the University of California Berkeley in 1959, Nestle went to earn a PhD in Molecular Biology in 1968 and an MPH in Public Health Nutrition in 1986, also from UC Berkeley. She is Paulette Goddard Professor in the Department of Nutrition, Food Studies, and Public Health at New York University, which she chaired from 1988-2003. From 2008 to 2013, she wrote Food Matters, a monthly food column in the San Francisco Chronicle.
Nestle received an honorary Doctor of Science degree from Transylvania University in 2012, and a James Beard Leadership Award in 2013, among many other awards. She has appeared as an expert in numerous films, including Super Size Me, Food Fight, and In Organic We Trust. In 2011, the University of California School of Public Health at Berkeley declared her a "Public Heath Hero." In Forbes magazine, food writer Michael Pollan named Nestle the "the world's #2 most powerful foodie," calling her "an indispensable voice on the problems of the American diet and their roots in industry marketing and government policy." New York Times writer Mark Bittman has described Nestle as "the #1 foodie to be thankful for," calling her an "all-around heroine" and noting that "many of those involved in the food movement [started] with Marion Nestle."
She has run a blog and web site, foodpolitics.com, since 2006 and a twitter account, @marionnestle, since 2009.
Sources: http://steinhardt.nyu.edu/faculty/Marion_Nestle
Related Materials
The James Beard Foundation Archive (MSS 214)
Les Dames d'Escoffier New York Archive (MSS 150)
Voices from the Food Revolution: People Who Changed The Way Americans Eat (MSS 309)
Noel Riley Fitch Julia Child Papers (MSS 323)
Cecily Brownstone Papers (MSS 134)
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Scope and Contents
The Marion Nestle Papers document Marion Nestle's career as an author, public figure, and professor in the nutrition, food studies, and public health fields. The collection primarily consists of materials involved in the creation of her books, including Nestle's notes, research files, correspondence, book tour plans, and book drafts. Printed materials including restaurant menus, and food event flyers, and conference programs comprise another significant component of the collection. Nestle's correspondence with other authors, professors, and individuals from the food studies movement as well as materials from her professional roles as the senior nutritionist at the Surgeon General, as a teacher at New York University, the University of California at Berkeley and San Francisco, and as a lecturer at food-related events, colloquia, and symposia constitute a smaller part of the collection. Nestle's role as an editorial reviewer and advisor appear in the correspondence and printed materials she collected. The bulk of Nestle's research files span the years 1980-2013.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated to NYU's Fales Library and Special Collections in several stages by Marion Nestle between 2004 and 2018. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2011.159, 2013.159.001, 2013.159.002, 2016.014, 2016.016, 2017.025, and 2018.069.
Websites were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In December 2011, https://www.foodpolitics.com/ was added as part of the Food Blogs Web Archive. In 2016, http://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-08-04/one-plus-one:-marion-nestle/7691372/ and http://mpegmedia.abc.net.au/news/oneplusone/video/201608/ONEs_Tx_0508_1000k.mp4 were added to the Marion Nestle Web Archive. No accessioning information was recorded for these websites.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual and born-digital materials that have not not been preserved may not be available to researchers.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Women in the food industry.; Food industry and trade; Pet food industry; United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Clippings (information artifacts); Food science and technology -- History.; Food writers.; Food industry and trade -- Safety measures; VHS; Audiocassettes.; Photographs.; Authors and publishers -- United States.; Manuscripts for publication.; Galley proofs.; Nutrition policy -- United States; Nestle, Marion; Child, Julia; Pollan, Michael; James Beard Foundation
- Series I: Food Politics
  Scope and Content
  Series I contains materials relating the writing of the book Food Politics which was published in 2002. Materials include drafts, editing notes, book tour information, an abridged version for audio book, and research files.
  - Subseries A: Drafts and Book Design
    Arrangement
    Material in Subseries A are arranged chronologically and reflect the editing date labeled by Marion Nestle.
    - Food Politics: Drafts, Reviews and Proposal, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Food Politics: Book Design and Permissions, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Food Politics: Drafts, Reviews and Proposal, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Book Design and Permissions: Food Politics, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Book Tour for Food Politics [1 of 2], 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Book Tour for Food Politics [2 of 2], 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Food Politics Updates--Revisions, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Abridgment of Food Politics for Audio Book [1 of 2], October 27, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Abridgment of Food Politics for Audio Book [2 of 2], October 27, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: Research Files
    Material has been arranged alphabetically by subject and reflect the original folder titles provided by Marion Nestle.
    - AIDS [1 of 2], 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - AIDS [2 of 2], 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Carnitine, 1984-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - CSPI [Center for Science in the Public Interest] [1 of 3], 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - CSPI [Center for Science in the Public Interest] [2 of 3], 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - CSPI [Center for Science in the Public Interest] [3 of 3], 1987-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Olestra [1 of 2], 1996-2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Olestra [2 of 2], 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Olestra Patents [1 of 2], 1992-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Olestra Patents [2 of 2], 1991-1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Olestra Regulations, 1995-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Olestra Studies [1 of 2], 1997-2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Olestra Studies [2 of 2], 1982-1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Procter & Gamble [1 of 4], 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Procter & Gamble [2 of 4], 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Proctor & Gamble [3 of 4], 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Proctor & Gamble [4 of 4], 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Statements and Letters, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Worksite Nutrition [1 of 2], 1987-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Worksite Nutrition [2 of 2], 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series II: Safe Food
  Series II contains material related to the writing of the book Safe Food first published in 2003 and then revised and expanded in 2010.
  Series II has been arranged into three subseries: Drafts, Biotechnology Research Files, and Food Safety Research Files. The division of reserach files into either Biotechnology reserach or Food Safety reserach is one that Marion Nestle created and reflects her original research schema. Each subseries is described in greater detail below.
  - Subseries A: Drafts
    Materials are arranged chronologically.
    - Safe Food Draft (photocopies), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Safe Food: Editing Correspondence and Drafts [1 of 2], 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Safe Food: Editing Correspondence and Permissions [2 of 2], 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Safe Food: Bacteria, Biotechnology, and Bioterrorism, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Safe Food: Design and Images, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Safe Food Book Tour, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Safe Food Corrections, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Safe Food Edits [1 of 4], 2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Safe Food Edits [2 of 4], 2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Safe Food Edits [3 of 4], 2010 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Safe Food Edits [4 of 4], 2010 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Biotechnology Research Files
    Subseries B is arranged alphabetically by the subject of the research file as originally designated.
    - Antibiotic Resistance, 1994-2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - AquAdvantage Salmon, 2009-2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Benefits of Biotechnology [1 of 3], 2000-2009 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Benefits of Biotechnology [2 of 3], 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Benefits of Biotechnology [3 of 3], 1981-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Biology and the Promise of Nutrition [1 of 2], 1999-2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Biology and the Promise of Nutrition [2 of 2], 1999-2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Biopham, 1999-2005 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Biosafety Protocol, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Biotechnology in Europe [1 of 4], 2002-2007 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Biotechnology in Europe [2 of 4], 1997-2003 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Biotechnology in Europe [3 of 4], 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Biotechnology in Europe [4 of 4], 1995-1999 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Books and Reviews, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - BST (Bovine Somatotrophin Hormone) [1 of 2], 1999-2009 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - BST (Bovine Somatotrophin Hormone) [2 of 2], 1995-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - BST (Bovine Somatotrophin Hormone) and Aging [1 of 2], 1986-1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - BST (Bovine Somatotrophin Hormone) and Aging [2 of 2], 1986-1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1980-1996 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1980-1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 2001-2009 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Council for Biotechnology Information, 2000-2003 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Developing Countries [1 of 2], 2001-2009 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Developing Countries [2 of 2], 1995-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Economics, 1994-2009 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - EPA [Environmental Protection Agency], 1994-2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Ethics, 1999-2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - FDA/USDA, 1992-2006 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Genetic Pollution, 2000-2007 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - GoldenRice, 1999-2011 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Hearings - FDA, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Hearings - Senate, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - [Ignacio] Chapela [Protest at University of California, Berkley], 2002-2009 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - International Biotechnology [1 of 2], 2003-2005 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - International Biotechnology [2 of 2], 1998-2003 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - International Food Information Council, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Labeling in the United States, 1998-2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lawsuits and Petitions, 1998-2001 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Legislation, 2000-2007 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Lobbying, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Monarch Butterfly, 1999-2002 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Monsanto Advertising Campaigns, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Monsanto Advertisements in the New York Times, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Monsanto Promotional Materials [1 of 2], 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Monsanto Promotional Materials [2 of 2], 1996-1999 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Monsanto [Research] [1 of 3], 1999-2010 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Monsanto [Research] [2 of 3], 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Monsanto [Research] [3 of 3], 1990-1997 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Monsanto-Roundup [Herbicide], 1991-2009 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Oregon Measure 27 [The Proposed Food Labeling Law], 2002 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Patents, 1998-2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Precautionary Principle, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Starlink Corn [1 of 4], 1999-2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Starlink Corn [2 of 4], 2001 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Starlink Corn [3 of 4], 1999-2001 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Starlink Corn [4 of 4], 1995-2001 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Biotechnology Surveys [1 of 3], 1997-2005 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Biotechnology Surveys [2 of 3], 1998-2001 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Biotechnology Surveys [3 of 3], 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - World Trade Organization, 1999-2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Allergies, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Biotechnology Resource Kit- American Dietetic Association (ADA), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Animals and the USDA [1 of 2], 2002-2008 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Animals and the USDA [2 of 2], 1994-2000 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Anti-Biotechnology, 1997-2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Anti-Biotechnology- Prodi Gene, 2002-2005 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Anti- Biotechnology- Pusztai Affair, 1998-2003 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Anti- Biotechnology- Sabotage, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Anti- Biotechnology- Turning Point Advertisements, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Food Safety Research Files
    Subseries C is arranged alphabetically by the subject of the research file as originally designated.
    - Acrylamide, 2002-2009 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Aflatoxin, 1978-2005 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Antibiotics [1 of 4], 2004-2008 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Antibiotics [2 of 4], 2001-2005 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Antibiotics [3 of 4], 1999-2001 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Antibiotics [4 of 4], 1976-1999 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Bill Marler and Food Safety, 2009 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Bioterrorism [1 of 2], 2001-2004 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Bioterrorism [2 of 2], 1983-2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bioterrorism - Afghan Food Relief, 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Bioterrorism - Anthrax, 2001-2010 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Bioterrorism Federal Reports (GAD, FDA, USDA), 2001-2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Bisphenol A, 2010 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Consumer Education [1 of 2], 1984-2010 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Consumer Education [2 of 2], 1986-2003 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Cooking Products, 1971-1985 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Costs [1 of 2], 2001-2003 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Costs [2 of 2], 1985-1997 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Dioxin, 2001-2003 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Environmental Contaminants, 1979-2004 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - FDA, 2006-2009 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - FDA Regulations [1 of 2], 1996-2007 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - FDA Regulations [2 of 2], 1977-1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Food Safety [1 of 2], 1996-1999 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Food Safety [2 of 2], 1996-1999 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Food Safety [1 of 3], 1972-1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Food Safety [2 of 3], 1972-1995 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Food Safety [3 of 3], 1972-1995 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Food Safety [1 of 3], 2000 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Food Safety [2 of 3], 2000 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Food Safety [3 of 3], 2000 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Health Department Regulations, 1997-2001 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - HIMP Program, 2000-2002 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Imports, 1999-2004 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - International Food Safety, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Irradiation [1 of 2], 1975-1999 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Irradiation [2 of 2], 1975-1999 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Irradiation [1 of 2], 2000 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Irradiation [2 of 2], 2000 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Lead, 1971-1998 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Military, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Outbreaks [1 of 2], 2004-2005 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Outbreaks [2 of 2], 1999-2003 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Outbreaks: E. coli - Con Agra Beef, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Outbreaks: Spinach E. coli 0157:H7 [1 of 2], 2006 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Outbreaks: Spinach E. coli 0157:H7 [2 of 2], 2006 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Outbreaks: Reports on Spinach E. coli 0157:H7 [1 of 2], 2006 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Outbreaks: Reports on Spinach E. coli 0157:H7 [2 of 2], 2006 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Outbreaks: E. coli - Taco Bell, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Outbreaks: Food-borne Illness, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Outbreaks: Food-borne Illness, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Outbreaks: Food-borne Illness, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Outbreaks: Food-borne Illness, 2010 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Outbreaks: Foot and Mouth Disease, 2001-2003 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Outbreaks - Incidents [1 of 2], 1993-2001 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Outbreaks - Incidents [2 of 2], 2000-2001 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Outbreaks: Melamine Contamination in China [1 of 2], 2008 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Outbreaks: Melamine Contamination in China [2 of 2], 2008 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Outbreaks - Microbial Contaminants, 1984-2009 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Packaging Materials, 1981-1991 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Pesticides, 1980-1998 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Public Health Reports, 1999-2001 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Single Food Agency/FSI [1 of 2], 1999-2007 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Single Food Agency/FSI [2 of 2], 1993-1999 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Toxins, 1975-1996 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - USDA [1 of 3], 1998-2001 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - USDA [2 of 3], 1996 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - USDA [3 of 3], 1995 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Series III: What to Eat
  Series III is comprised of drafts and editing notes for the writing of the book What to Eat published in 2006.
  Material is arranged chronologically
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [1 of 8], undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [2 of 8], undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [3 of 8], undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [4 of 8], undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [5 of 8], undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [6 of 8], undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [7 of 8], undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat Edited Draft [8 of 8], undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat Early Page Designs, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat Various Iterations of Cover Art, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat Edited Book Draft (cover; contents; chapter 23; chapter 12; notes), undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat Editing Correspondence [1 of 2], 2003-2005 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat Editing Correspondence [2 of 2], 2003-2005 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - What to Eat Introduction Correspondence, 2004-2006 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Copyedited Manuscript of What to Eat [1 of 4], October 4, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Copyedited Manuscript of What to Eat [2 of 4], October 4, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Copyedited Manuscript of What to Eat [3 of 4], October 4, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Copyedited Manuscript of What to Eat [4 of 4], October 4, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat Draft Pages with Comments, October 31, 2005; February 9-10, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [1 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [2 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [3 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [4 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [5 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [6 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [7 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [8 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 2)